Guide to the Jazz Loft Project Records, 1950-2012 and undated RL.10001
David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library
- Oral Histories, 1991-2010; 614 items
  - Stevenson, James, 2003 June 16; Archival Resource Key; 97
    In this oral history, Stevenson discusses arriving in New York City with other musicians and becoming almost immediately strung out on drugs. He also talks about his family history with music, his relationship with W. Eugene Smith, and his encounters with musicians at the Jazz Loft including Rahsaan Roland Kirk, Chick Corea, Sonny Clark, and Zoot Sims.
    - James Stevenson Transcript, 2002-2008 (Box 8, Folder 32)
    - James Stevenson, 6/16/03, I, Digital audio tape, Recorder original, 2003 June 16 (Box 21, Audio-cassette RL10001-DAT-0116)
    - James Stevenson, 6/16/03, II, Digital audio tape, Recorder original, 2003 June 16 (Box 21, Audio-cassette RL10001-DAT-0117)
    - James Stevenson, 6/16/03, III, Digital audio tape, Recorder original, 2003 June 16 (Box 21, Audio-cassette RL10001-DAT-0118)
    - James Stevenson, I, 6/16/03, Mini-dv videocassette, Recorder original, 2003 June 16 (Box 23, Video-cassette RL10001-MDV-0111)
    - James Stevenson, II, 6/16/03, Mini-dv videocassette, Recorder original, 2003 June 16 (Box 24, Video-cassette RL10001-MDV-0112)
    - James Stevenson, III, 6/16/03, Mini-dv videocassette, Recorder original, 2003 June 16 (Box 24, Video-cassette RL10001-MDV-0113)
    - James Stevenson, I, 6/16/2003, Compact disc, Transcription copy, 2003 June 16 (Box 30, Audio-cd RL10001-CD-0051)
    - James Stevenson, II, 6/16/03, Compact disc, Transcription copy, 2003 June 16 (Box 30, Audio-cd RL10001-CD-0052)
    - Untitled, digital audio tape, 2004 June 17 (Box 24, Audio-cassette RL10001-DAT-0139)
    - Untitled, digital audio tape, 2004 June 17 (Box 24, Audio-cassette RL10001-DAT-0140)
  - Suris, Sherry, 2004 August 12; Archival Resource Key; 98
    Sherry Suris was a young freelance photographer from New York when she became romantically involved with Gene Smith at the end of his marriage to Aileen. Sherry was with him in Tucson at the end of his life.
    - Sherry Suris, 8-12-04, Digital audio tape, Recorder original, 2004 August 12 (Box 21, Audio-cassette RL10001-DAT-0119)
  - Tentchoff, Ivan, 2005 September 22; 99
    Ivan Tentchoff, a school teacher, and his wife, Marilyn, were very close to the Smith family. He was something of a surrogate father for the Smith children in Croton-on-Hudson.
    In this oral history, Pat Smith (son of W. Eugene Smith) and Ivan Tentchoff discuss the dynamics of the Smith household, their own friendship, and W. Eugene's Smith life and work. In particular, Pat talks about his father's creative process and borderline obsessive behavior when it came to making art. Ivan talks about befriending the family and looking out for Pat during Smith's frequent absences.
    - Ivan Tentchoff/Pat Smith Transcript, 2002-2008 (Box 8, Folder 31)
    - Ivan Tentchoff, Pat Smith, 9/22/05, Digital audio tape, Recorder original, 2005 September 22 (Box 21, Audio-cassette RL10001-DAT-0114)
    - Ivan Tentchoff & Pat Smith, 9/22/05, Standard Audio-cassette, Transcription copy, 2005 September 22 (Box 28, Audio-cassette RL10001-CS-0114)
  - Thomas, Carole, 2003 June 20; Archival Resource Key; 100
    Carole Thomas (b. 1941) was born in New York, NY. She came to Gene Smith as a student in 1959. They subsequently fell in love and had an on-and-off relationship because of Smith's problems with alcohol and drugs. She lived in the Jazz Loft building with him from 1959-1968, and her support was probably essential to him staying alive and accomplishing what he did during that period. Thomas was an artist and designer with a background in theater design, which made her a perfect companion for Smith, who was fascinated by the visual qualities of theater throughout his life. She comes across in conversation as a very sharp and sympathetic figure on many of Smith's loft tapes.
    In this oral history, Thomas talks about her time as W. Eugene Smith's assistant and goes into great detail about Smith's creative process, his health struggles and addictions, and his relationships with other artists and musicians. Thomas also discusses the Jazz Loft and its many visitors/inhabitants including Roland Kirk, Ronnie Free, and Freddy Greenwell. Other topics include Thomas's personal life in New York City and California and her personal development as an artist.
    - Carole Thomas Transcript, 2002-2008 (Box 8, Folder 33)
    - Carole Thomas, 6/20/03, I, Digital audio tape, Recorder original, 2003 June 20 (Box 21, Audio-cassette RL10001-DAT-0120)
    - Carole Thomas, 6/20/03, II, Digital audio tape, Recorder original, 2003 June 20 (Box 21, Audio-cassette RL10001-DAT-0121)
    - Carole Thomas, 6/20/03, 1 of 2, Compact disc, Transcription copy, 2003 June 20 (Box 30, Audio-cd RL10001-CD-0053)
    - Carole Thomas, 6/20/03, 2 of 2, Compact disc, Transcription copy, 2003 June 20 (Box 30, Audio-cd RL10001-CD-0054)
    - Carole Thomas, I/2, 6/20/03, Santa Monica, CA, Froman's Restaurant (Sam), Standard Audio-cassette, Transcription copy, 2003 June 20 (Box 28, Audio-cassette RL10001-CS-0115)
    - Carole Thomas, 6/20/03, I/2-cont'd, II/2, Standard Audio-cassette, Transcription copy, 2003 June 20 (Box 28, Audio-cassette RL10001-CS-0116)
    - Carole Thomas, II/2, cont'd ~ 5 min, Standard Audio-cassette, Transcription copy, 2003 June 20 (Box 28, Audio-cassette RL10001-CS-0117)
  - Tofani, Dave, 2004 August 12; Archival Resource Key; 101
    Dave Tofani was born in Williamsport, PA. While majoring in saxophone and clarinet performance at the Juilliard School, Tofani studied under Hall Overton. He later played in a band with Overton and Lee Konitz that rehearsed often in the Jazz Loft.
    - Dave Tofani, 8-12-04, I, Digital audio tape, Recorder original, 2004 August 12 (Box 21, Audio-cassette RL10001-DAT-0122)
    - Dave Tofani, 8/12/04, II, Digital audio tape, Recorder original, 2004 August 12 (Box 21, Audio-cassette RL10001-DAT-0123)
    - Dave Tofani, I, 8-12-04, Mini-dv videocassette, Recorder original, 2004 August 12 (Box 24, Video-cassette RL10001-MDV-0114)
    - Dave Tofani, II, 8-12-04, ~23 min., Mini-dv videocassette, Recorder original, 2004 August 12 (Box 24, Video-cassette RL10001-MDV-0115)
    - Dave Tofani, 8-12-04, I, Standard Audio-cassette, Transcription copy, 2004 August 12 (Box 28, Audio-cassette RL10001-CS-0118)
    - Dave Tofani, 8-12-04, I (part 2), (a few seconds), Standard Audio-cassette, Transcription copy, 2004 August 12 (Box 28, Audio-cassette RL10001-CS-0119)
    - Dave Tofani, 8/12/04, II, Standard Audio-cassette, Transcription copy, 2004 August 12 (Box 28, Audio-cassette RL10001-CS-0120)
    - Untitled, Audio-cassette, undated (Box 24, Audio-cassette RL10001-CS-0145)
  - Tolliver, Charles, undated; 102
    Charles Tolliver (b 1942) was born in Jacksonville, FL. A trumpter and bandleader, Tolliver participated in jam sessions circa 1963-64. He was featured in the 2009 reenactment the 50th anniversary of Thelonious Monk's historic Town Hall concert.
    - John Bouille, Charles Tolliver, Digital audio tape, Recorder original, undated (Box 21, Audio-cassette RL10001-DAT-0015)
  - Turner, Beth, 2009 September 23; Archival Resource Key; 103
    Beth Turner conributed to the Jazz Loft Project.
    - Beth Turner - CDS, 9-23-09, Sam S., Dan P., [illegible], Mini-dv videocassette, Recorder original, 2009 September 23 (Box 24, Video-cassette RL10001-MDV-0116)
    - Beth Turner, 9-23-09, @CDS, Sam S. int., Standard Audio-cassette, Transcription copy, 2009 September 23 (Box 28, Audio-cassette RL10001-CS-0121)
  - Vestal, David, 2005 September 20; Archival Resource Key; 104
    David Vestal (b 1924) was born in Menlo Park, CA. He was an accomplished photographer and writer. Vestal made a great photograph of Smith after he came across him wandering around Sixth Avenue in the mid-1960s after his loft had been robbed by junkies. Vestal also wrote one of the best pieces about Smith ever published, attempting to debunk the mythology surrounding Smith's battles with Life's editors. The article, "A Great Unknown Photographer – W. Eugene Smith," was published in Popular Photography in December 1966.
    In this oral history, Vestal goes into great detail about his background and training as a photographer, including stories about attending the Art Institute, studying Lazlo Moholy-Nagy, and taking classes with Sid Grossman of the famed Photo League. Vestal also discusses W. Eugene Smith life, work, and relationships at length.
    - David Vestal Transcript, 2002-2008 (Box 8, Folder 34)
    - David Vestal, 9/20/05, I, Digital audio tape, Recorder original, 2005 September 20; 62 minutes (Box 21, Audio-cassette RL10001-DAT-0124)
    - David Vestal, 9/20/05, II, Digital audio tape, Recorder original, 2005 September 20; 64 minutes (Box 21, Audio-cassette RL10001-DAT-0125)
    - David Vestal, 9/20/05, III, Digital audio tape, Recorder original, 2005 September 20; 13 minutes (Box 21, Audio-cassette RL10001-DAT-0126)
    - David Vestal, 9-20-05, Bethlehem, NY, 1/3, Mini-dv videocassette, Recorder original, 2005 September 20 (Box 24, Video-cassette RL10001-MDV-0117)
    - David Vestel, 2/3, 9-20-05, Bethlehem, NY, Mini-dv videocassette, Recorder original, 2005 September 20 (Box 24, Video-cassette RL10001-MDV-0118)
    - David Vestal, 9-20-05, Bethlehem, NY, 3/3, Mini-dv videocassette, Recorder original, 2005 September 20 (Box 24, Video-cassette RL10001-MDV-0119)
    - David Vestal, 9/20/05, I, Standard Audio-cassette, Transcription copy, 2005 September 20 (Box 28, Audio-cassette RL10001-CS-0122)
    - David Vestal, 9/20/05, II, Standard Audio-cassette, Transcription copy, 2005 September 20 (Box 28, Audio-cassette RL10001-CS-0123)
    - David Vestal, 9/20/05, III (and end of II), Standard Audio-cassette, Transcription copy, 2005 September 20 (Box 28, Audio-cassette RL10001-CS-0124)
  - Vlachos, Mitchell, 2006 October 10; Archival Resource Key; 105
    Harry Mitchell Vlachos (1926-2010) was born in New York, NY. He inherited and owned his father's flower shop-- Vlachos Wholesale Florist--which still operates today on 28th Street between Sixth Avenue and Broadway, a couple of doors down from Zero Mostel's loft and near the Jazz Loft.
    In this oral history, Vlachos discusses the Flower District in New York City, his father's flower shop, and the neighborhood culture during the time of the Jazz Loft. Vlachos goes into detail about local businesses, city politics, and his family history.
    - Mitchell Vlachos Transcript, 2002-2008 (Box 8, Folder 35)
    - Mitchell Vlachos, 10/10/06, Digital audio tape, Recorder original, 2006 October 10 (Box 21, Audio-cassette RL10001-DAT-0127)
    - (Harry) "Mitchell" Vlachos, 10-10-6, Mini-dv videocassette, Recorder original, 2006 October 10 (Box 24, Video-cassette RL10001-MDV-0120)
    - Mitchell Vlachos, 10/10/06, Compact disc, Transcription copy, 2006 October 10 (Box 30, Audio-cd RL10001-CD-0055)
  - Wald, Ted and Virginia Wald, 2005 June 25; Archival Resource Key; 106
    Ted Wald (b 1929) was born in New York City. He was a bass player who took part in many loft jam sessions in the early 1960s. In the summer of 1961, he met teenager Virginia McEwan in the loft and married her many years later, and they eventually settled together in Port Townsend, WA.
    In multiple interviews, the Walds talk about their experiences at the Jazz Loft (where they first met in 1961) and their interactions with of its inhabitants and visitors including Freddy Greenwell, Tom Wayburn, and Lee Konitz. Ted discusses what it was like to perform at gigs in the city and making jazz recordings. Both talk about W. Eugene Smith and his living space in the Jazz Loft. Virginia also talks about her relationships with other musicians including Paul Butterfield and Lin Halliday (who first took her to the Jazz Loft). Of particular note is Virginia's story about Lin Halliday and Sonny Clark taking drugs in the 4th floor hallway of the Jazz Loft building.
    - Ted and Virginia Wald Transcript, 2002-2008 (Box 8, Folder 36)
    - Ted Wald, 6-25-05, I, Digital audio tape, Recorder original, 2005 June 25 (Box 21, Audio-cassette RL10001-DAT-0128)
    - Ted Wald, 6-25-05, II, Digital audio tape, Recorder original, 2005 June 25 (Box 21, Audio-cassette RL10001-DAT-0129)
    - Ted Wald, 6-25-05, III, Digital audio tape, Recorder original, 2005 June 25 (Box 21, Audio-cassette RL10001-DAT-0130)
    - Ted & Virginia Wald, 6-25-05, IV, Digital audio tape, Recorder original, 2005 June 25 (Box 21, Audio-cassette RL10001-DAT-0131)
    - Ted Wald, 1/3, Port Townsend, WA, 6/25/05, Mini-dv videocassette, Recorder original, 2005 June 25 (Box 24, Video-cassette RL10001-MDV-0121)
    - Ted Wald, 2/3, 6-25-05, (+ Virginia Wald), 2/5, Mini-dv videocassette, Recorder original, 2005 June 25 (Box 24, Video-cassette RL10001-MDV-0122)
    - Ted Wald, 3/3 (3/5 w/Virginia), 6-25-05, Port Townsend, WA, Mini-dv videocassette, Recorder original, 2005 June 25 (Box 24, Video-cassette RL10001-MDV-0123)
    - Virginia Wald, w/Ted Wald, 1/2, 6/[?]/05, Mini-dv videocassette, Recorder original, 2005 June 25 (Box 24, Video-cassette RL10001-MDV-0124)
    - Virginia Wald + Ted Wald, 6/25/05, 2/2 = End of Day, Mini-dv videocassette, Recorder original, 2005 June 25 (Box 24, Video-cassette RL10001-MDV-0125)
    - Ted Wald, 6-25-05, I, Standard Audio-cassette, Transcription copy, 2005 June 25 (Box 28, Audio-cassette RL10001-CS-0125)
    - Ted Wald, 6-25-05, II, Part 1, Standard Audio-cassette, Transcription copy, 2005 June 25 (Box 28, Audio-cassette RL10001-CS-0126)
    - Ted Wald, 6-25-05, II Part 2, & III, Standard Audio-cassette, Transcription copy, 2005 June 25 (Box 28, Audio-cassette RL10001-CS-0127)
    - Ted & Virginia Wald, 6-25-05, IV, Standard Audio-cassette, Transcription copy, 2005 June 25 (Box 28, Audio-cassette RL10001-CS-0128)
  - Warren, Butch, undated; 108
    - Butch Warren Transcript, 2002-2008 (Box 8, Folder 37)
  - Wayburn, Tommy, 2003 May 28; Archival Resource Key; 109
    Thomas Wayburn (b 1934) was born and raised in Detroit, MI. A jazz drummer, Wayburn lived next door to 821 Sixth Avenue for a while and was there often in the early 1960s. He had a job translating Russian journals into English and he can be heard talking about this on Smith's tapes. He later became a chemical engineer.
    In this oral history, Wayburn talks about his development as a musician including his studies with Lennie Tristano, his work as a chemical engineer, and his relationships with various jazz performers including Lou Orensteen, Sonny Clark, and Jimmy Stevenson. Wayburn talks about the loft culture in great detail, mentioning the rehearsals and jam sessions that happened in his own space, as well as others that happened at the Jazz Loft on 6th Avenue. Also of note is Wayburn's discussion of W. Eugene Smith and his memories of other musicians who happened to be at the Jazz Loft.
    - Tom Wayburn Transcript, 2002-2008 (Box 8, Folder 38)
    - Tom Wayburn, 5/28/03, I, Digital audio tape, Recorder original, 2003 May 28; 65 minutes (Box 21, Audio-cassette RL10001-DAT-0133)
    - Tom Wayburn, 5/28/03, II, Digital audio tape, Recorder original, 2003 May 28; 65 minutes (Box 21, Audio-cassette RL10001-DAT-0134)
    - Tom Wayburn, 5/28/03, III, Digital audio tape, Recorder original, 2003 May 28; 13 minutes (Box 21, Audio-cassette RL10001-DAT-0135)
    - Tom Wayburn, I, Mini-dv videocassette, Recorder original, 2003 May 28 (Box 24, Video-cassette RL10001-MDV-0126)
    - Tom Wayburn, II, Mini-dv videocassette, Recorder original, 2003 May 28 (Box 24, Video-cassette RL10001-MDV-0127)
  - Williams, Howard, 2001 May 17; Archival Resource Key; 110
    Howard Williams was born in Little Rock, AR. Williams, a pianist, was one of several musicians from Little Rock who found their way to the loft at 821 Sixth Avenue. Williams lived in 823 Sixth Avenue around 1959 and remembers hearing Thelonious Monk and Hall Overton working in the loft by themselves and later with Monk's full Town Hall band.
    In this oral history, Williams talks about the importance of the loft to the development of the jazz music scene in New York. In particular, Williams talks about living in the building next door to the Jazz Loft, his interactions with Eugene Smith, and his memory of hearing Thelonious Monk's rehearsals for the 1959 Town Hall Concert.
    - Howard Williams Transcript, 2002-2008 (Box 8, Folder 39)
    - Howard Williams, 5/17/01, Ira Jackson, 5/19/01, Digital audio tape, Recorder original, 2001 May 17 (Box 21, Audio-cassette RL10001-DAT-0060)
    - Howard Williams, 5/17/01, Ira Jackson, 5/19/01, Part 1, Standard Audio-cassette, Transcription copy, 2001 May 17 (Box 28, Audio-cassette RL10001-CS-0131)
    - Howard Williams, 5/17/01, Ira Jackson, 5/19/01, Part 2, Standard Audio-cassette, Transcription copy, 2001 May 17 (Box 28, Audio-cassette RL10001-CS-0132)
    - Howard Williams, Ira Jackson, Part 3, Standard Audio-cassette, Transcription copy, 2001 May 17 (Box 28, Audio-cassette RL10001-CS-0133)
    - Howard Williams, 5/17/01, Ira Jackson, 5/19/01, Standard Audio-cassette, Transcription copy, 2001 May 17 (Box 28, Audio-cassette RL10001-CS-0134)
  - Wilson, John, 2003 July 27; Archival Resource Key; 111
    John Wilson was a jazz trumpeter. He participated in several recording sessions with Jimmy Raney and Hall Overton in the mid-1950s and attended jam sessions and rehearsals in the Jazz Loft.
    In this oral history, Wilson discusses his musical background, his time in the Army during World War II, and his involvement with the loft jazz scene in New York City. Wilson talks about studying at the Manhattan School of Music, playing with the Benny Goodman Band, and his experiences interacting with various people at the Jazz Loft including Jimmy Stevenson and Zoot Sims
    - John Wilson Transcript, 2002-2008 (Box 8, Folder 40)
    - John Wilson, 7/27/03, I, Digital audio tape, Recorder original, 2003 July 27 (Box 21, Audio-cassette RL10001-DAT-0136)
    - John Wilson, 7/27/03, II, Digital audio tape, Recorder original, 2003 July 27 (Box 21, Audio-cassette RL10001-DAT-0137)
    - John Wilson, 7/27/03, I, Mini-dv videocassette, Recorder original, 2003 July 27 (Box 24, Video-cassette RL10001-MDV-0128)
    - John Wilson, 7/27/03, II, Mini-dv videocassette, Recorder original, 2003 July 27 (Box 24, Video-cassette RL10001-MDV-0129)
    - John Wilson, I and II, 7/27/03, Standard Audio-cassette, Transcription copy, 2003 July 27 (Box 28, Audio-cassette RL10001-CS-0135)
    - John Wilson, II cont'd, 7/27/03, Standard Audio-cassette, Transcription copy, 2003 July 27 (Box 28, Audio-cassette RL10001-CS-0136)
  - Woods, Phil, 2002 January 15; Archival Resource Key; 112
    Phil Woods (b 1931) was born in Springfield, MA. An alto saxophonist, he studied with Hall Overton early in his career and participated in many jam sessions at the loft. Woods was also a member of Thelonious Monk's big bands that rehearsed in the loft in 1959, 1963, and 1964.
    In multiple interviews, Woods talks about coming to NYC at age 15, attending Manhattan School of Music, and becoming deeply involved with the jazz scene. Woods also goes into great detail about playing at Birdland with Dizzy Gillespie, performing with Thelonious Monk at the 1959 Town Hall Concert, his relationship with Zoot Sims, and his experiences at the Jazz Loft with a host of musicians.
    - Phil Woods Transcripts, 2002-2008 (Box 8, Folder 41)
    - Phil Woods, 1/15/02, Nancy Overton, 3/1/02, Digital audio tape, Recorder original, 2002 January 15 (Box 21, Audio-cassette RL10001-DAT-0092)
    - Phil Woods, 1/15/02, Nancy Overton, 3/1/02, Part 1, Standard Audio-cassette, Transcription copy, 2002 January 15 (Box 28, Audio-cassette RL10001-CS-0137)
    - Phil Woods, 1/15/02, Nancy Overton, 3/1/02, Part 2, Standard Audio-cassette, Transcription copy, 2002 January 15 (Box 28, Audio-cassette RL10001-CS-0138)
  - Woodson, Dorrie, 2008 April 09; Archival Resource Key; 113
    Dorrie Woodson (b 1934) was born in Salisbury, PA. A pianist, she moved to New York in 1955 and found her way to 821 Sixth Avenue on the suggestion of Teddy Charles, whom she had met a few months earlier at a gig in Baltimore. At 821 she met photographer Harold Feinstein, who lived there at the time, and the two married and lived together in the loft until 1957.
    In this oral history, Woodson talks about her relationship with photographer Harold Feinstein and their experiences living at the Jazz Loft. Woodson also discusses her background as a musician and her memories about performing jazz music in New York City.
    - Dorrie Woodson, 11/12/10, Compact disc, Transcription copy, 2010 November 12; 58 minutes (Box 30, Audio-cd RL10001-CD-0056)
    - Dorrie Woodson, 4/9/08, Compact disc, Transcription copy, 2008 April 09; 39 minutes (Box 30, Audio-cd RL10001-CD-0057)
    - Dorrie Glenna[?] Woodson, 4/9/08, Compact disc, Transcription copy, 2008 April 09 (Box 30, Audio-cd RL10001-CD-0058)
    - Dorrie Woodson, 4/9/08, w/Sam Stephenson, Compact disc, Transcription copy, 2008 April 09 (Box 30, Audio-cd RL10001-CD-0059)
  - Yellin, Pete, 2000 October 28; Archival Resource Key; 114
    In this oral history, saxophonist Pete Yellin talks about coming onto the New York jazz scene in the 1950's, where he met Ronnie Cuber at a very young age. Yellin goes into detail about playing at jam sessions in various lofts, including Jimmy Stevenson's, Tom Wayburn's, and the building known as the Jazz Loft. Also of note are Yellin's memories about Sonny Clark, Gil Coggins, Lin Halliday, and Ron Free.
    - Pete Yellin Transcript, 2002-2008 (Box 8, Folder 42)
    - Ronnie Cuber 10/26/00, Pete Yellin 10/28/00, Digital audio tape, Recorder original, 2000 October 28 (Box 21, Audio-cassette RL10001-DAT-0020)
    - Ronnie Cuber, Pete Yellin, 10/00, Part 1, Standard Audio-cassette, Transcription copy, 2000 October 28 (Box 25, Audio-cassette RL10001-CS-0022)
  - Young, David X., 1998 June 07; Archival Resource Key; 115
    David X. Young (1930-2001) was born in Eastham, Massachusetts. A painter interested in jazz music, he moved into the fifth floor of the loft at 821 Sixth Avenue with Overton, Cary, and Feinstein in 1954. Young bought a piano and opened the loft to jazz musicians. He moved to a different loft in 1960, where he lived until his death.
    - David X. Young/Eugene Smith Transcripts, 2002-2008 (Box 8, Folder 43)
    - David X Young, I, 6/7/98, (1-2), Standard Audio-cassette, Transcription copy, 1998 June 07 (Box 28, Audio-cassette RL10001-CS-0139)
    - David X Young, I, 6/7/98, cont'd (3), Standard Audio-cassette, Transcription copy, 1998 June 07 (Box 28, Audio-cassette RL10001-CS-0140)
    - David X. Young /7/98, microcassette, 1998 June 07 (Box 24, Audio-cassette RL10001-MCS-0002)
  - Zitrin, Arthur, 2007 July 16; Archival Resource Key; 116
    Arthur Zitrin (b 1918) was an imminent psychiatrist affiliated with New York University Medical School and Bellevue Hospital. He also co-produced several historical documentaries and was an avid anti-death penalty activist.
    In this oral history, Zitrin discusses his affiliation with Bellevue Hospital, his experiences co-producing documentary movies, and his memories about fellow psychiatrist Nathan Kline. W. Eugene Smith was once admitted to Bellevue and, later on, sought out care from Nathan Kline. While Zitrin did not know Smith, he talks about the dangers of alcoholism, Kline's psychiatric methods, and what Smith's illnesses might have been like.
    - Arthur Zitrin, 7-16-07, Digital audio tape, Recorder original, 2007 July 16 (Box 21, Audio-cassette RL10001-DAT-0138)
- Research Notes, Articles, and Materials